export const CQuestion = [
  {
    question:
      "Which symbol is used for the modulus operator in C?Which symbol is used for the modulus operator in C?",
    ans: 1,
    option: ["%", "#", "$", "&"],
  },
  {
    question: "In C, which keyword is used to define a constant?",
    ans: 2,
    option: ["constant", "const", "#define", "def"],
  },
  {
    question: "What is the correct way to declare a pointer variable in C",
    ans: 2,
    option: ["int ptr;", "ptr int;", "int *ptr;", "pointer ptr;"],
  },
  {
    question: "Which function is used to dynamically allocate memory in C",
    ans: 3,
    option: ["calloc()", " realloc()", "malloc()", "All of the above"],
  },
  {
    question: "How do you access the first element of an array in C?",
    ans: 2,
    option: ["arr[1]", "arr[-1]", "arr[0]", "arr[first]"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the format specifier to print a floating-point number in C?",
    ans: 0,
    option: ["%f", "%s", "%c", "%d"],
  },
  {
    question: "What is the result of 7 / 3 * 2",
    ans: 2,
    option: ["2.333", " 4.666", "4", "6"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the maximum value that can be stored in an 'unsigned int' in C?",
    ans: 2,
    option: ["32767", "65535", "4294967295", "2147483647"],
  },
  {
    question: "How do you exit a loop prematurely in C?",
    ans: 1,
    option: ["continue", "break", "exit", "return"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following statements is true about arrays in C language?",
    ans: 0,
    option: [
      "The array size must be known at compile time",
      "The array size can be changed during runtime",
      "Arrays cannot be passed as function arguments",
      "Arrays can only store one type of data",
    ],
  },
];
